<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Tobacco Control Playbook]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[The tobacco playbook of arguments illustrates how the industry players act to oppose tobacco control measures and how governments and the public health community can respond to their arguments.]]></description>
        <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/index.html</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 07:44:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <copyright><![CDATA[WHO Regional Office for Europe]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <managingEditor><![CDATA[tobaccofree@euro.who.int (WHO Regional Office for Europe)]]></managingEditor>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <category><![CDATA[second-hand smoke]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[health effects]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[smokefree legislation]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[exposure]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[indoor public places]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[enforcement]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco products]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[product packaging]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco industry]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[warnings]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[plain packaging]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[smokefree policy]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[public places]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[hospitality industry]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco marketing]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[young people]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco advertising]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[promotion]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[sponsorship]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[Illicit tobacco trade]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco taxation]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco market]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[smuggling]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[counterfeiting]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco prices]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[health intervention]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[revenue]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco consumption]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[public health]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[Trade law]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[trade agreements]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[WHO FCTC]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[WTO]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[case law]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[investment law]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[sovereign right of states]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[commercial rights]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[intellectual property]]></category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Comprehensive smokefree legislation is essential in protecting the health of others]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Evidence strongly and consistently indicates that second-hand smoke has serious effects on the health of others and that the only way to protect people from it is to implement comprehensive smokefree legislation in all indoor places where others are present. The tobacco industry has tried to deter the implementation of smokefree legislation by shifting focus onto other issues using industry-funded so-called science, and front groups to spread the misleading argument that ventilation or partial smoking restrictions are adequate.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/001-comprehensive-smokefree-legislation.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">eb1a8c6ea5acabc2111c529e664d27ce</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Large pictorial pack warnings and plain packaging work]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Evidence has consistently shown that pictorial warnings on tobacco packs effectively communicate the health risks of tobacco use to wider audiences, including children and illiterate people, and that the positive effects of pictorial warnings are strengthened with larger graphic warnings and plain packaging. Implementing these measures is key in protecting people from tobacco; however, the tobacco industry has consistently fought the implementation of large, pictorial warnings and plain packaging in favour of either no warnings or, at best, vague text warnings.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/002-packaging.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">85f4d02f87e13ea1727ab29a1771af22</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smokefree legislation does not harm the hospitality industry]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Smokefree legislation has a positive impact on the hospitality industry. Damage to the industry is a myth: rigorous studies have shown that these measures have a positive or neutral effect, discounting industry claims that are mostly based on poorly designed studies.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/003-smokefree-legislation.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">81f0ed7b4a2d1b2d66709de79b0fc602</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tobacco marketing is targeted at children and young people]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The tobacco industry has targeted children and young people for decades in its advertising, promotion and sponsorship programmes, primarily to recruit replacement smokers – to replace those who have quit or died from diseases caused by smoking – and to create new markets. In protecting children from tobacco, it is essential to restrict all tobacco advertising, promotion and sponsorship, and to take steps to normalize tobacco-free lifestyles.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/004-marketing.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6f69b8db31e61701ab3f566db35fe9f9</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tobacco taxation does not result in illicit trade]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Illicit tobacco trade exists as a result of poor control of organized smuggling and inadequate tobacco control measures, and counterfeiting more than as a result of tobacco taxation. To curb illicit tobacco trade, it is essential to secure comprehensive strategies for tackling criminal activities while keeping tobacco taxes high as part of a comprehensive approach to reducing smoking.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/005-illicit-trade.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e85d1a6ce65b955d6c8e7170ef9919f7</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tobacco taxation is one of the most cost-effective health interventions: government revenues increase while smoking rates fall]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Tobacco taxes are a fast and effective way to reduce tobacco consumption while simultaneously generating revenues for the state, at relatively little cost. The tobacco industry argues that increasing tobacco taxes will lead to a loss of jobs and revenue due to declining smoking rates; the truth, however, is that increased taxes create a win-win situation for public health and the economy as revenue increases even as smoking rates fall.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/006-taxation.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2ddc9a11649e62c29f63c740d35a7848</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WTO law provides regulatory space for tobacco control measures]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[International trade agreements recognize the sovereign right of states to regulate in the interests of public health, as confirmed by case law.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/007-regulatory-space.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a473c5d821b22075d860426b9acab104</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Governments can enact tobacco control public health measures without infringing the tobacco industry’s commercial rights]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[International trade and investment law recognize the sovereign right of states to regulate in the interests of public health as confirmed by international instruments, World Trade Organization (WTO) case law and investment arbitral tribunal decisions.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/008-commercial-rights.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4559090c4661cd15c1b97730e0ebc5a0</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>