<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Tobacco Control Playbook]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[The tobacco playbook of arguments illustrates how the industry players act to oppose tobacco control measures and how governments and the public health community can respond to their arguments.]]></description>
        <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/index.html</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 08:20:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <copyright><![CDATA[WHO Regional Office for Europe]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <managingEditor><![CDATA[tobaccofree@euro.who.int (WHO Regional Office for Europe)]]></managingEditor>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <category><![CDATA[second-hand smoke]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[health effects]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[smokefree legislation]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[exposure]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[indoor public places]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[enforcement]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco products]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[product packaging]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco industry]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[warnings]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[plain packaging]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[smokefree policy]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[public places]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[hospitality industry]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco marketing]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[young people]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco advertising]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[promotion]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[sponsorship]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[Illicit tobacco trade]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco taxation]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco market]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[smuggling]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[counterfeiting]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco prices]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[health intervention]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[revenue]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[tobacco consumption]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[public health]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[Trade law]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[trade agreements]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[WHO FCTC]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[WTO]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[case law]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[investment law]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[sovereign right of states]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[commercial rights]]></category>
        <category><![CDATA[intellectual property]]></category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Comprehensive smokefree legislation is essential in protecting the health of others]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Evidence strongly and consistently indicates that second-hand smoke has serious effects on the health of others and that the only way to protect people from it is to implement comprehensive smokefree legislation in all indoor places where others are present. The tobacco industry has tried to deter the implementation of smokefree legislation by shifting focus onto other issues using industry-funded so-called science, and front groups to spread the misleading argument that ventilation or partial smoking restrictions are adequate.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/001-comprehensive-smokefree-legislation.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1b0aa1a07a0046363f3c3feb856b7b00</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Large pictorial pack warnings and plain packaging work]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Evidence has consistently shown that pictorial warnings on tobacco packs effectively communicate the health risks of tobacco use to wider audiences, including children and illiterate people, and that the positive effects of pictorial warnings are strengthened with larger graphic warnings and plain packaging. Implementing these measures is key in protecting people from tobacco; however, the tobacco industry has consistently fought the implementation of large, pictorial warnings and plain packaging in favour of either no warnings or, at best, vague text warnings.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/002-packaging.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">df594b0e63d4019dd16664f693b695d8</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smokefree legislation does not harm the hospitality industry]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Smokefree legislation has a positive impact on the hospitality industry. Damage to the industry is a myth: rigorous studies have shown that these measures have a positive or neutral effect, discounting industry claims that are mostly based on poorly designed studies.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/003-smokefree-legislation.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">220c2a73753cf43ebc8a7b694d7dccff</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tobacco marketing is targeted at children and young people]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The tobacco industry has targeted children and young people for decades in its advertising, promotion and sponsorship programmes, primarily to recruit replacement smokers – to replace those who have quit or died from diseases caused by smoking – and to create new markets. In protecting children from tobacco, it is essential to restrict all tobacco advertising, promotion and sponsorship, and to take steps to normalize tobacco-free lifestyles.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/004-marketing.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6f69b8db31e61701ab3f566db35fe9f9</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tobacco taxation does not result in illicit trade]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Illicit tobacco trade exists as a result of poor control of organized smuggling and inadequate tobacco control measures, and counterfeiting more than as a result of tobacco taxation. To curb illicit tobacco trade, it is essential to secure comprehensive strategies for tackling criminal activities while keeping tobacco taxes high as part of a comprehensive approach to reducing smoking.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/005-illicit-trade.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0ab46fafa971ea4e1fa188b2403a1305</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tobacco taxation is one of the most cost-effective health interventions: government revenues increase while smoking rates fall]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Tobacco taxes are a fast and effective way to reduce tobacco consumption while simultaneously generating revenues for the state, at relatively little cost. The tobacco industry argues that increasing tobacco taxes will lead to a loss of jobs and revenue due to declining smoking rates; the truth, however, is that increased taxes create a win-win situation for public health and the economy as revenue increases even as smoking rates fall.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/006-taxation.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4691145176c3b318cbcf6f332d6c50e1</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WTO law provides regulatory space for tobacco control measures]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[International trade agreements recognize the sovereign right of states to regulate in the interests of public health, as confirmed by case law.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/007-regulatory-space.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a473c5d821b22075d860426b9acab104</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Governments can enact tobacco control public health measures without infringing the tobacco industry’s commercial rights]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[International trade and investment law recognize the sovereign right of states to regulate in the interests of public health as confirmed by international instruments, World Trade Organization (WTO) case law and investment arbitral tribunal decisions.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/008-commercial-rights.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a5dd83aa60d5ece59133394b2133903d</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is tobacco smoking a free and informed choice?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Tobacco smoking is highly addictive and, in most cases, starts in childhood. The tobacco industry's marketing, research and public relations activities are a source of misinformation. These issues make it difficult for people to make free and informed choices about tobacco smoking.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/009-free-and-informed-choice.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b5178761b9e051f51832bcd5c7654303</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is smoking cessation beneficial for people with mental illness, and can they quit?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Quitting smoking improves mental health conditions. People with mental illness are as motivated and able to quit as those without. To improve the physical and mental health of patients, encouraging and supporting smoking cessation should be a priority in the mental health treatment setting.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/010-cessation-for-people-with-mental-ilness.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">efd202ac6343c850d2f037fc5b2134d6</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is there public support for tobacco control measures?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[There is strong public support for tobacco control measures, even from people who smoke. Surveys in various countries show that comprehensive measures such as smoke-free indoor and outdoor areas, bans on point-of-sale tobacco displays, plain packaging and tobacco taxation are welcomed by the public.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/011-public-support.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">78c6b37f1a47477cbd004bb756c43026</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does every tobacco control measure result in catastrophe?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[In countries where effective tobacco control measures have been implemented, catastrophic outcomes predicted by the tobacco industry – such as public uproar, illicit trade or negative economic impacts – have simply not materialized.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/012-does-tobacco-control-measure-result-in-catastrophe.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">78bc580970a27e4b5460ac6bb7fc659a</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Do tobacco companies take a responsible approach to education and information?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[There is overwhelming evidence that tobacco companies continue to make massive efforts to mislead the public about the harms of smoking, deny and undermine the evidence, and to oppose strong public education programs that would present the evidence effectively.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/013-education-and-information.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1014bf06903074d300e1727c4781b0ab</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is action on smoking the first step on a slippery slope?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Tobacco is uniquely harmful, requiring unique approaches. There are some similarities with other preventable health problems and harmful behaviours, but also differences. Action on tobacco recommended by health authorities is evidence-based, proportionate to the magnitude of the problem and will prevent millions of unnecessary deaths.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/014-slippery-slope.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8820b8109cb27f9193771fc11d12d551</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Does tobacco control harm tobacco growers?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Tobacco control measures do not harm growers. It does not lead to a sudden drop in leaf demand. It is the extremely monopolized tobacco industry that creates a weak bargaining position for farmers, causing poverty and other harms in tobacco farming regions.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/015-tobacco-growers.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ed216680d7ea2c81544191226e0b3b95</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Special issue: judicial statements from legal action involving the tobacco industry]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/016-judicial-statements.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2316103da14bd0c5229a82560f82ce83</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Special issue: judicial statements from legal action involving the tobacco industry (cont.)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/017-judicial-statements-cont.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8b26b47268c5130a6afe320c2f1aa924</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Do longer, healthier lives have a positive overall effect on the economy?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Tobacco-free initiatives help people to live longer and more healthily, which in turn has a positive economic impact. The financial benefits gained from investing in a more productive, healthy society far outweigh the costs, and there is plenty of evidence from various countries to support this.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/018-positive-effect-on-economy.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6f51ccaa85db2bf427a0023f1874c598</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smoking is an adult behaviour and smokers are aware of the risks]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Smoking is not an adult behaviour. Most smokers start as children, and around the world millions of children are smokers. Tobacco companies have a long history of targeting children and young people, exposing them to a wide range of advertising and other forms of marketing, and seeking to prevent measures that will reduce smoking in children and young people.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/019-adult-behaviour.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ca1352e015118cd569785670ac1a27b6</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is the tobacco industry a normal, legitimate industry?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Tobacco is not a normal industry: it is the world’s most lethal industry, which products cause 7 million deaths each year around the world. The tobacco industry has not changed despite the evidence for the harm it causes: its primary role remains to sell as many cigarettes as possible, and it still seeks to oppose any action that might reduce sales.]]></description>
            <link>https://tobaccoplaybook.net/en/020-most-lethal-industry.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">274489fe6faea62e20f9a72242983f2c</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>